Actions you take are answered by the
consequences waiting at their conclusion.
行動の果てには結果という答えが
待っている　例外はない
There are no exceptions.
And Lelouch's power is no use against them.
そこにルルーシュの力は及ばない
いかなる相手にでも命令を下せる
絶対遵守の力を持っていようと
Even though he possesses the absolute
power to make anyone to obey him,
there is no escape from the inevitable.
その必然からは逃れられない
He took these actions
to avenge his mother's death.
母の仇を討つ為に
Lelouch also took them to create a world for
his younger sister, Nunnally, to live in happily.
妹 ナナリーが
幸せに過ごせる場所を作る為に
動き出したルルーシュ
However, the world... People have forced him
to face consequences he never expected,
だがしかし 世界は 人々は
彼の思惑とは別に
結果を突きつけ その続きを求めてくる
and they ask for more.
If you say that such escalation
will weave out a new world,
その続きが
世界を紡いでいくというのなら
then who shall be charged
with the crimes committed...
誰かが負うべき罪は 受けるべき罰は
and will there be punishment
for them to accept?
いったい どこにあると いうのだろう
Yumemiteta yume
The dream that I dreamed
夢見てた夢
果て無き遠く
Hatenai tooku
Endless and distant
乾いた日々の 空色・手の中
Kawaita hibi no sorairo, te no naka
The sky-blue of dry days, in my hands
Toukankaku oto no naka de
In the space between each tick of the clock
等間隔 音の中で試行錯誤
Shikousakugo
Trial and error
時間・間隔の無い空間
Jikan kankaku no nai kuukan
A space without distance or time
Toushindai oto wo tatete
Making a life-sized sound
等身大 音をたてて
僕の顔　造って行く
Boku no kao tsukutte yuku
It defines my face
Kirei ni katahou dake
Cleanly, but only one side
キレイに　片方だけ
Kono te ni ochita
This rotting apple...
この手に落ちた
Kusarikake no ringo
That's fallen into my hand
腐りかけのリンゴ
Kagami ni utsuru
Reflecting in the mirror
鏡に映る　僕らの裏側まで
Bokura no uragawa made
Even showing our other side
遠感覚 人の中で試行錯誤
Toukankaku oto no naka de
In the space between each tick of the clock
Shikousakugo
Trial and error
時間・感覚の無い空間
Jikan kankaku no nai kuukan
A space without distance or time
頭身台 爪をたてて
Toushindai tsume wo tatete
With life-sized claws bared
Boku no kao wo kezutte yuku
I shave my face
僕の顔　削って行く
Kirei ni katahou dake
Cleanly, but only one side
キレイに　片方だけ
Toukankaku
A distant sensation
－遠感覚
Toukankaku
A distant sensation
GEASS VS. GEASS
指令より401 敵を撃破しつつ
９時方向に移動
Command to 4-0-1! Move to
9 o'clock to suppress the enemy!
You'll be under Sir Charing's command after that!
以後 チャリング卿の指揮下に入れ
Special suppression unit C.P.
to all Knightmare units!
Scramble code alpha! Alpha-Niner! Alpha-Niner!
Confirm current situation and report!
Unit 9-0-3! Alpha-Niner, confirmed!
Wait!
待て！
深追いするな！
今は総督の守りが最優先だ
Do not pursue! Protecting the
viceroy has top priority here!
くう
Zero! Come in, Zero!
ゼロ！　応答してくれ
ゼロ！
扇か？　私だ　C.C.だ
Ohgi, is that you? It's me, C.C.
ゼロはどうなった？
How's Zero?
無事だが今は動けない
お前が撤退命令を出せ
He's all right, but can't move now.
Issue the order to retreat.
If you keep this up, you'll be wiped out.
もたつくと全滅するぞ
そっ… そうだな　分かった
Y-Yeah, you're right. Got it.
んん？
これでいいのか？
Are you sure about this?
あっ ああ…
珍しいな　指示も出せないほど
動揺するとは
This is unusual. You're so shaken up you
can't even issue orders. Now, Cornelia...
コーネリアなら…
違う！　銃が無くなっているんだ
You're wrong. My gun's disappeared.
俺が気絶してる間に誰かが持って行った
Someone took it while I was still unconscious.
という事は…
お前の素顔を見られた？
Which means...
They saw your face.
少なくとも２人…
There were at least two people.
撃った奴と撃たれた奴　２人いる
The shooter and the one who
was shot. Two people were here.
あぁ…
うっうぅ…
Shirley?
シャーリー？
うっ…
こんな朝早くから何してんの？
What are you doing up so early?
手紙？
A letter?
う うん… ちょっとね
Uh, no. It's nothing.
ひょっとして ラブレターとか？
Or maybe it's a love letter.
相手はルルーシュ？
Is it for Lelouch?
えっ？
ふ… そう かな…
Maybe it is...
ユーフェミア殿下に会いたい？
You want to meet Princess Euphemia?
おっ お礼 お礼がしたくって
To... To thank her! Just to thank her...
ホテルジャックの時 ニーナの事
体を張ってかばってくれたのよ
She risked herself to protect
Nina during the hotel jacking.
自分はユーフェミアですって名乗り出て
She just jumped out, saying "I'm Euphemia!" Right?
ね！
I see.
そう…
俺も会いたい
I want to meet her, too!
どーして？
Why?
だってお姫様だよ？　逆玉じゃん
Well, she's a princess!
I can marry my way to royalty!
そういう不純な動機の人は
会えないと思います
I don't think she'd meet someone
with such indecent motives.
不純って…
Indecent?
うあっ
Nunnally, you can be so direct!
ナナリーちゃんて結構きっついな
ねっ 会長さん
Right, Ms. President?
ルルーシュが
構ってくれないから といって
Just because Lelouch isn't hanging out with you,
don't go turning your evil affections on me!
よこしまな情動をこっちに向けるな
えへへ… でも 私も会ってみたいな
ユーフェミア殿下に
Still, I'd like to meet Princess Euphemia, too.
えっ
あっ
どうなんですか？　スザクさん？
What about it, Suzaku?
いや でも… 向こうは雲の上の人で
Well, I mean...
She's part of the imperial court, so...
あっ
はい アッシュフォード学園生徒会です
Hello, Ashford Academy student council.
あ？
スザクか？
Suzaku?
ルルーシュ？
Lelouch?
あっ
そっち 何か変わった事はないか？
Is there anything... unusual over there?
あるよ
Yeah, there is.
ん！
君がいない
You're not here.
あのなぁ
Now, look...
Although Shirley hasn't shown up yet, either.
シャーリーも まだ
顔を出せないみたいだけど
You've been cutting classes lately.
You have to take school more seriously!
最近授業も休みがちだし
もうちょっと ちゃんと学生やりなよ
ふっ この優等生め
Hmpf! Says the honor student!
ナナリーに伝えてくれないか
今日は遅くなるって
Can you give Nunnally a message for me?
Tell her I'll be home late tonight.
今日はじゃなくて 今日もだろ？
Not just "tonight."
You mean "tonight, again."
こんなに会えないんじゃ
なんの為に同じ学校なんだか…
What's the point of going to the
same school if I never see you?
ウニャー
うわっ！
ん どうした？
Hm? What's wrong?
いや なんでも…
Um, nothing.
Darn it, Arthur! Agh!
こら！　アーサー… うわあ！
何遊んでいるんだ あいつ
What kind of game is he playing over there?
その様子だと…
So, from what you can see...
ああ スザクは知らないようだ
Right. It seems Suzaku doesn't know about me.
これで軍に見られたという線は消えたな
So, that eliminates the possibility
that I was seen by the military.
軍と黒の騎士団以外に
あんな所に来る奴がいるとは思えないな
Aside from the military and the Black Knights,
I can't think of anyone else
who would have come there.
日本解放戦線の生き残り…
という線もある
There is the possibility that it was a
survivor of the Japan Liberation Front.
銃だけ盗んだ？
Who then just stole your gun?
扇にはブラックマーケットを
探らせている
I'll have Ohgi search the black market.
血液は？
What about that blood?
採取はしたが 時間がかかる
It's been collected, but it'd
take too long. Besides that...
それと…
あの戦場でシャーリーを見た気がする
I thought I saw Shirley there at the battle.
ああ お前とキスした女か
Oh, the girl who kissed you?
あぁっ… しつこいな
Let it rest!
確認しただけだ 色ガキめ
Just making sure it was her, lover boy.
しかし だとすると私達が当面
探るべきは…
But if that's true, then the thing we have
to find out most urgently would be...
今回の作戦といい ナリタ連山といい
明らかに姫様を狙った行動です
Both this last operation and the
one in the Narita mountains.
What's clear is that they were specifically
targeting you, Your Highness.
頭を叩くのは戦の常道だ
Attacking the head is a standard tactic in combat.
クロヴィス殿下の事もあります
There's also what happened to Prince Clovis.
うっ
ゼロは ブリタニアという体制よりも
Zero may not just be attacking the Britannian order.
ブリタニア皇族に対する
恨みで動いている可能性があります
It's possible he may be motivated by hatred
for the Britannian royal family as well.
恨み？
Hatred?
ユーフェミア 民衆の為に
人質をかって出たか
Euphemia... You gave yourself up
for the sake of the commoners?
相変わらずだな
You haven't changed.
気をつけろよ？　ユフィ
Be careful, Euphy.
え？
もうホテルジャックのような事は
ごめんだ
I don't want any repeats of that hotel jacking.
騎士を持たれては いかがでしょう
Why not assign a knight to her?
A knight?
騎士？
警護役をユーフェミア様の
専任騎士とすれば
If Princess Euphemia has a
knight to guard her full-time,
その者を中心に親衛隊を構築できます
then we can build a royal guard for her around him.
ユーフェミア様は副総督ですから
既にその権利はお持ちかと…
Princess Euphemia already has
the right to one as the sub-viceroy.
最初は根が優しいから
なんだろうと思っていました
At first, I thought it was
because he's so gentle at heart.
しかし 人命に対する反応が
過敏過ぎると思いませんか？
But don't you think he tends to
fixate on saving peoples' lives?
でもね 実動データには問題ない訳だし
Still, there's no problem with the
performance data he's giving us.
ついでに あれを試してみようかと
思うんだけど…
and to be honest, I'd like to put
that thing to the test with him.
まだ調整中です
We're still fine-tuning the system.
それと スザク君をパーツ扱い
する しない にかかわらず
Besides that, regardless of treating
Suzaku like part of a machine,
きちんと向き合わないと
何も見えないし 伝わりませんよ
if we don't deal with this properly,
we won't see or learn anything from him.
あのさ　君こそ彼を
誰かと被せて見ていない？
Pardon, but aren't you treating
him like more than a colleague?
はっ… さぁ どうでしょう
Well, I'm not sure. Still...
でも…
Hm?
んん？
変なところだけ 気が回るんですね
Still, you are quick to notice
silly things like that, aren't you?
うふふ… これでも上司だから
Well, It's because I'm your boss.
何やってんの？　こんなとこで
What are you doing here?
待ってるのよ
お部屋の殺菌消毒が終わるの
Waiting for them to finish disinfecting my room.
どうして私が
他人の下着を漁らねばならんのだ
Why must I have to go rifling
through some stranger's underwear?
この貸しは高いぞ
This is going to cost you!
分かっている
Understood.
ふっ お前がやった方が早いものを
You could do it faster. And she wouldn't
mind the boy she likes doing it.
あの女だって好きな男になら…
こっちの問題だ
That's my problem.
また変なところに こだわって
You get hung up about the littlest things.
しかし 見当たらないな 銃は
Still, there's no sign of that gun in here.
日記も14日までしか書いていないし
And her diary is only written up to the 14th...
14日…
The 14th?
ああ
Yeah.
彼女の父親が 亡くなった日だ
That's the day that her father died.
あっ
ん？
これは…
What are?
お前の写真だな
Photos of you.
俺の？
Of me?
いじらしいじゃないか　容疑者にしては
How sweet.
How can you suspect her?
よせ　そんな言い方は
Stop saying it like that!
あっ
ナリタ
Narita.
ルル… どうしてこんな事を
Lulu... How could you have done this?
さあ どうしてだろう
Yes, how indeed?
え？　あ…
立派な慰霊碑だね
シャーリー・フェネットさん
A fine memorial, Miss Shirley Fenette.
えっ 誰？
Wh- Who?
惜っしい事したよなぁ もう少しで…
Man, it was so close! We nearly had her!
次は白兜も まとめて倒すから
Next time, I'll beat that White Helmet for sure.
Quit worrying about it.
気にするなって
そうそう 玉城なんかすぐ
やられちゃって
Yeah, right, Tamaki was beaten right away.
はっはっは…
解放戦線の船
The J.L.F. ship...
えっ？
どうして爆発したのかな？
Why did it explode?
自爆だろ
It self-destructed, right?
連絡はしたんだよな？　助けるからって
We told them that we'd help them, didn't we?
その為にゼロが動いたんじゃないか
That's why Zero took action.
あっ そっか！
顔を見るチャンスだった？
Oh, I know. It was a chance to see his face!
わははっ…
まさかゼロを疑ってるんじゃあ…
You're not doubting Zero, are you?
いや でも…
No, but...
あまりにもタイミングが良過ぎると？
You think the timing was just too convenient, right?
もしあれがゼロの仕業だとしたら
どうするつもりです？
What do you plan to do if that
was all really Zero's doing?
何？　その言い方
And just what are you implying?!
おい ディートハルト
この前は怖くて逃げ出したらしいな
Hey, Diethard!
I heard you turned chicken and ran!
チキンなブリキ野郎が 俺達幹部に
向かってタメ口聞いてんじゃねえ
A chicken shit Brit's got a lot of nerve
talking that way to his superiors!
戦況の把握に努めただけです
扇さんも認めてくれましたが
I was just trying to see how the battle was going.
Ohgi, you could see that, right?
ええっ？
あ… あぁ ゼロも構わないって
Y-Yeah. Even Zero said it was all right.
好きなのか？　シャーリーとかいう女を
So, do you love this "Shirley" girl?
さあな
I don't know.
嫌いなのか？
Do you hate her?
さあな
I don't know.
では なぜナリタに行く
Then why are we going to Narita?
正体を知られた可能性があるからに
決まっているだろう
Because there's a possibility
she knows my identity, right?!
知られていたら どうする
始末するのか？
And if she does know, what then?
Do we kill her?
あっ…
本当に失いたくないものは
遠ざけて おくものだ
Anyone you really don't want to
lose should be kept at a distance.
それは… 経験か？
Is that experience talking?
いや… 生き方だ
No. It's how I live.
ひどい男だね ルルーシュは
Lelouch is a cruel man, isn't he?
どうして ルルの事も
How do you know about Lulu, too?
騙していたんだろう？
ホントはゼロなのに
He had you fooled, didn't he?
Even though he's actually Zero.
あっ… 誰なの？　あなた
Who are you?!
彼は 君のお父さんを
殺す命令を出した その口で
The same mouth which ordered your
father's death stole a kiss from your lips.
君の唇を奪ったんだよ？
許せないよね そんなの
I would think that would be unforgivable.
う…
罰を受けなくては いけない
Punishment must be mete out.
彼も 君も
To him. And to you.
私…
Me?!
全部知ってるよぉ
I know everything.
Everything that happened that night...
あの夜の事はね
うぅ… はっはっ…
そいつがゼロか！
Is that Zero?!
はっ
これは驚きだな
学生自身がゼロだったとは
Well, this is a surprise.
The student is Zero himself!
しかもブリタニア人　うっふっふ…
A Britannian, as well.
あははは…
こいつをコーネリア総督に差し出せば
私は貴族になれる
They're going to make me nobility when
I present him to Princess Cornelia!
騎士候なんかじゃない 本物の貴族にだ
Not a Knight of Honor, but real nobility!
それに まだ生きている
And he's still alive!
いいぞ　どんな処刑がお似合いかな？
Good. What sort of execution will suit you?
総督には お前の事も… はっ
The viceroy will reward you as well...
はぁぁ…
うかつ… お前の男だったな！
Stupid of me...
He's your boyfriend, isn't he?!
あぁっ
Lulu!
You're a murderer, too. Just like Zero.
君も殺人者　ゼロと同罪だね
あぁ 違う 私は…
No! I just!
その上 父親の死と引き換えに
対価まで得て
On top of that, in exchange for your
father's death, you actually profited!
No! I just... I just!!!
違う 私は… 私は！
ずるい女　彼に優しさを期待して
わざと哀れに振る舞った
Cunning woman!
You pretended to look miserable
so that he'd feel sorry for you.
違う… 違う！
You're wrong! You're wrong!
同情の視線は心地良かったかい？
Did his sympathetic gaze make you feel good?
やめて！
Stop it!
いつまで悲劇のヒロインでいるつもり？
How long do you plan to play the tragic heroine?
そんな事 思ってない！
I'm not trying to!
人を殺して男を漁る君は
ヒロインなんかじゃない
Heroines don't kill people to gain a
boy's love. It's evil witches who do that.
醜悪な魔女だよ
You're wrong! I...
違う　私は…
ルルーシュを好きな女が他にもいるのを
知ってて 彼のそばにい続けた
You knew there was another girl who likes
Lelouch, so you wanted to be the one at his side.
あ… はっ…
君は報いを受けるべきだ
You have to pay the price.
はっ あぁ…
はぁぁ…
そんな気持ちを 一生引きずる？
Will you carry these feelings for the rest of your life?
たった１人で抱え込んで
Bearing them all by yourself?
罪を償い 心を解き放たないと
Unless you atone for your sins
and free your heart,
君もルルーシュも
あまりに かわいそうだよ
you and Lelouch
will be all the more pitiful.
CODE GEASS
Lelouch of the Rebellion
うっ ここだと思ったんだが…
I thought she'd be here.
We'll just have to split up and look for her.
手分けして探すしかないな
Do you know what Shirley looks like?
分かるのか？　シャーリーの顔が
What's with you now?
何を今さら
ふっ
可能性は低い　いるはずがないんだ
The possibility's so slim.
I doubt she's even here.
知られていたら どうする
始末するのか？
And if she does know, what then?
Do we kill her?
いや 待て　もう１人いるはずだろう
No, wait.
There has to be another one.
Where are they?
And what were they doing with Shirley?
そいつはどこに　そいつとシャーリーは
えい　落ち着け！　もう一度初めから
Calm down.
Work it back from the beginning.
あっ
Shirley?!
シャーリー？
俺だ　今どこにいる！
It's me. Where are you?!
さあ どこかな
Ah, where indeed?
あっ
誰だ お前は！
Who are you?!
あ… 貴様 シャーリーに何を！
You son of a!
What have done to Shirley?!
あぁ いいねえ　怖い顔だ
自分の女を奪われて許せない って顔
Ooh, I like it! The scary face!
The unforgiving face of a man whose
woman has been taken from him.
シャーリーはどこだ！
Where's Shirley?!
知りたい？　じゃあ 勝負しようよ
得意なんだってねえ 君
You want to know?
Then I challenge you.
You specialize at this, don't you?
I don't have a photo. I can draw you
a Batuan style portrait, if you like.
写真はない
絵画ならバトゥアンスタイルで
描き終わるまで待てっての？
勘弁してよ
What, I'm supposed to wait till you
finish drawing it? No, thank you.
軍や警察に頼んだ方が早いって
It'd be faster to just ask the
military or the police, wouldn't it?
つまらないピンチを招く気はない
I'd like to avoid a dull crisis like that, if possible.
じゃ 高い所からでも見渡せばぁ？
Well, why not climb up on
something tall and look around?
分かった　もういい
Very well. Never mind, then.
Hm? What's Lelouch up to now?
なんだ？　ルルーシュの奴
あ…
まさか　マオ！
It can't be... Mao!
Is this him? The other witness?
こいつか　もう１人の目撃者は
恐らくチェスは ひっかけに過ぎない
I'll wager this chess game is just a distraction.
本当の目的は 俺を人気のない場所に
連れ出す事
His real objective is to lure me
someplace with no other people.
僕 初めてやるんだよねえ このゲーム
I've never played this game before.
Was he just being theatrical by
calling me on my cell phone?
携帯にかけてきたのも演出？
いや 俺の顔を知らないからだ
No, it was because he didn't know what I look like.
Meaning he didn't have enough
time to get a photo of me.
つまり 俺の写真を
手に入れる時間がなかったという事
周到に準備された作戦ではない
This plan hasn't been meticulously
thought through. If that's the case, then...
だとすれば…
There's an opening you can use?
付け入る隙はある？
あ…
Shouldn't you concentrate
a bit more on our game?
もうちょっと勝負に集中した方が
いいんじゃない？
負けちゃうよ？
You'll lose, otherwise.
えい　何が初めてだ 嘘つきめ！
You're no beginner, you liar!
ルルーシュ お前では… いや
お前だからこそ マオには勝てない
Lelouch, even you...
No, because of who you are,
you'll never be able to beat Mao!
うう…
バカな　この俺が…
Impossible... He's beaten me?!
あっ はっ
So, can I assume that I've won?
ねぇ これって僕の勝ちで
いいのかなあ？
俺が完璧に読み負けるなんて
何者だ こいつは？
How can he always predict
my moves? Who is this guy?!
聞いてないの？　C.C.に
Didn't C.C. tell you about me?
うっ… あっ
さすがだね　僕の正体について
一瞬で14の可能性を考えつくなんて
Well done! You instantly thought
of 14 possible identities for me.
しかもその内の１つは 大正解
And one of them is extremely correct.
うぉっ　ギアス能力者！
A Geass user?!
Oh, wait! You can't use your Geass unless
you have direct contact with a person's eyes.
おっと 君のギアスは相手の目を
直接見なければ使えない
そういうルールも全部
分かっちゃうんだよねぇ
I know all the rules to your little gift.
思考を読んだ？
You're a mind reader?!
そういうギアスなんだよ 僕のは
That's pretty much what my Geass is.
シャーリーを撃ったのか！
Did you shoot Shirley?!
Did you... Did you kill her?!
お前が… お前がシャーリーを！
Of course not!
まさか
あっ　シャーリー
Shirley!
Now then, let the punishment game begin.
さてと… 罰ゲームを始めようか
ゼロ… 昨日の君は らしくなかった
Zero... You weren't yourself yesterday.
どうして そんな気がするんだろう
Why do I feel this way?
おっ
大丈夫ですか？
Are you all right?!
しっかりして　おい！　君！
Speak to me! Hey! C'mon!
うっ
あっ 生きてる
You're alive!
そうか お前が… ゼロ
So... It's you... Zero...
あっ
Shirley... That gun is!
シャーリー その銃は？
うん　ゼロの… ルルの銃だよ
Yeah. It's Zero's. Your gun.
くっ…
使いなよ ギアス
Why not use your Geass?
うう…
You haven't used it on her yet, have you?
まだ彼女には かけた事ないはずだろ？
うう…
Although, if you use it, I'll shoot at once.
もっとも そんな事をしたら
すぐに撃っちゃうけどね
Can he only read surface thoughts?
読めるのは表層だけか？　俺みたいに
ギアスを使う条件はあるのか？
Are there conditions that his
Geass has to obey, like mine?
タイムラグは？　持続時間は？
そもそも目的はなんだ？
A time lag? A time limit?
And besides that, what is he after?!
If he plans to kill me, then...
俺を殺すつもりなら…
ほーら考えなよ　お得意の策略をさ
くるくるくるくるーって
Go on, think about it.
You love games of strategy, right?
The way you spin thoughts
around and around...
黙れ！
Shut up!
泥棒猫にはこういう死に方がふさわしい
This is a fitting death for a thief like you.
ああ？
ルル… 死んで
Lulu... Die.
あっ
罪を償おう？
私も一緒に死んであげるから
Why not atone for our crimes?
I'll even die with you.
何？
What?
彼女も撃っちゃったんだよ
もう１人の目撃者を
She actually shot the other witness.
君の秘密を守る為にね
All to protect your secret.
Then, that blood was...
じゃあ… あの血痕は？
もう 終わりにしよう ルル…
Let's end this, Lulu.
そうそう 罪には罰をね
Yes, yes. Crime must be punished, after all.
貴様 シャーリーを…
You put her up to this!
はっ
When you think about it, it'd be easy for a mind
reader to manipulate people into doing things.
思考が読めれば
人を操り 誘導するのは たやすい
Yes, exactly!
うん その通り
騙されるな シャーリー！　あいつは
Don't be fooled, Shirley! He's!
Oh, please! That's you, isn't it?
The one who tricked her.
おいおい 君の方だろう？
彼女を騙していたのは
やめて！
Stop it!
人殺しが罪だというなら
罪を重ねるな！
If murder is a crime,
then don't compound it with more!
Well done! Your rhetoric is admirable!
うまい！　ものは言いようだねえ
ええぃ
本当に殺したのか？　あいつに
そう誘導されただけじゃないのか？
Did you really kill anyone?! Are you sure
he isn't just making you think that you did?!
彼女は自分で気づいたのさ
隠し続ける事に意味なんかないって
She realized it herself.
There was no point in hiding it anymore.
そんな事はない！　シャーリー！
That's not true, Shirley!
もう黙って！
Just shut up!
うっ
ぐぁっ
う…
はっ
はぁぁ…
はぁ
Why are you hesitating?
He killed your father!
何をためらってる
そいつは 君の父親を殺したんだぞ
殺せ… そいつはただの人殺しだ
Kill him!
He's just a murderer.
でも…
But...
Shirley!
シャーリー！
I... I!
私… 私は…
なんだよ この女
考えがぐちゃぐちゃだ
What's with this girl? Her thoughts are
just a jumble now. Never mind, I'll just...
もういいや 僕が…
ぐぁっ
やめて… やめてー！
Stop it! STOP IT!!!
Fine. Fine, whatever.
分かった 分かってるから…
あとは２人でご自由に
You're both free to do what you want.
うっ あぁ…
シャーリー！
Shirley!
あぁっ
なんだよ
ドラマチックにしてあげたのに
What's the big idea?
I had it all going so dramatically.
つまんないけど ２人まとめて…
Well, it may be boring, but I'll just take
care of them both the direct way...
うおっ
うっ 誰だ！　僕が気づかないなんて
Who's there?! How could
I not have sensed them?!
It couldn't be!
まさか！　うぁっ
C.C.！
C.C.!
やっぱりそうか　ようやく会えた
君に… 本当の君に！
I knew it! We finally meet again!
It's you! It's really you!
Are you awake, Mao?
起きたのか マオ　すまなかったな マオ
Forgive me, Mao.
That's the way.
See, Mao? You can do it.
そうだ マオ できるじゃないか
ありがとう マオ
Thank you, Mao.
ふはは…
You look wonderful, even in that outfit, C.C.!
そういう格好も素敵だね C.C.
C.C.会いに行く
すぐに会いに行くから 必ず 必ず！
C.C., I'll come to see you!
I'll come see you as soon as I can!
I swear! I SWEAR!
マオ… お前が人の群れの中に
出てくるなんて
Mao...
I never thought you'd show up in a crowd.
シャーリー もういいんだ もう
Shirley, it's all right now. It's over.
ルル… 私 人を撃っちゃったの
だから…
Lulu, I shot someone. That's why I...
俺のせいだ　シャーリーは悪くない
It's my fault. You did nothing wrong.
ルルの事も撃った
And I shot you...
俺は生きてる
I'm alive.
でも… ルルを撃ったの
But I still shot you!
俺が許す　君の罪は 全部俺が
I forgive you.
Any sin you committed is mine to bear.
優しくされようとした
I wanted you to be kind to me...
What's wrong with that?
何がいけない
お父さんが死んだのに…
Even though my father is dead now!
忘れるんだ
嫌な事は 全て忘れてしまえばいい
Just forget it. You should forget all
the bad things that have happened.
できないよ！
- I can't!
できる！
- You can!
- I can't!
ええ？
俺が全部忘れさせてやる
I'll let you forget all of this.
まさか
Impossible.
Shirley... I'm sorry about what
happened to your father.
シャーリー お父さんの事はすまなかった
もし生まれ変わる事ができたら
君に…
If I could be reborn,
then you and I would be...
ルル… ダメー！
Lulu... NO!!!
あの…
Excuse me, did you lose family, too?
あなたもご家族を亡くされたんですか？
いえ 家族ではなく
No, not family.
友達を… そう たぶん 大事な
A friend. Someone... who may
have been very important to me.
そうですか
I see.
失くしてから
初めて分かる事ってあるんですね
I only realize how important
now because I've lost her.
自分がどれだけ 彼女の笑顔に
救われてきたかって
Just how much I was saved by her smile.
もう あんなふうに口喧嘩する事も
笑い合う事もできないんだなって…
And how I'll now never be able to
bicker or laugh with her like that again.
好きだったんですね　その人の事
You loved her, didn't you?
今は… もう分かりません
Right now...
I don't know anymore.
Morning will come.
朝は来ますよ
えっ
私 さっきまで何しにここまで来たのか
分かんなくなって いたんですけど
I've forgotten exactly why
I came out here in the first place.
もしかしたら 何か区切りを
付けたかったのかもしれません
Maybe because I wanted to
put something behind me.
そりゃあ 忘れる事なんて
できっこないし
Well, there are some things I just can't forget.
悲しい事って いっぱいあるけど
And a lot of sad things, too.
でも 朝は来るじゃないですか
But morning still comes, right?
だから無理して押さえ込んでも…
That's why you shouldn't try to
hold thoughts like that back.
そうですね　俺もそう思っています
Yeah, you're right. I feel the same way.
今まで… ありがとう
Thank you. For everything.
え？
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
モザイクカケラ ひとつひとつ
Hitotsu hitotsu tsunagiawasete
Coming together one by one
繋ぎ合わせて描いてゆく
Egaiteyuku
To form the picture
あなたがくれた 出逢いと別れも
Anata ga kureta deai to wakare mo
The meetings and partings I've had with you
こんなはずじゃない そう思って眠り
Konna hazu ja nai
"It can't be," I think
Sou omotte nemuri
As I go to sleep
Mezamereba itsumo no
When I awaken, just as always
目覚めればいつもの 変わらない空回り
Kawaranai karamawari
I'm left going nowhere
意味も無く繰り返し
Imi mo naku kurikaeshi
Pointlessly repeating the pattern
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
モザイクカケラ 鮮やかに映す
Azayaka ni utsusu
Clearly showing
過去の嘘も過ちも
Kako no uso mo ayamachi mo
The lies and mistakes of the past
消してしまいたいと想えば想うほど
Keshiteshimaitai to omoeba omou hodo
As much as I'd like to erase them
Furikaereba soko ni aru
When I look back, I see...
振り返れば
そこにあるスタートライン
Start line mada susun ja inai
I still haven't moved past that start line
未だ進んじゃいない
もう一度夢を拾い集めてみよう
Mou ichido yume wo
So let's try regathering
Hiroiatsumete miyou
the pieces of our dream
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
モザイクカケラ ひとつひとつ
Hitotsu hitotsu tsunagiawasete
Coming together one by one
繋ぎ合わせて描いてゆく
Egaiteyuku
To form the picture
Anata ga kureta deai to wakare mo
The meetings and partings I've had with you
あなたがくれた 出逢いと別れも
確かに俺は甘いのかもしれない
Perhaps I was too soft.
シャーリーを始末すれば
良かったのかもしれない
Perhaps it would have been
better to have just killed Shirley.
しかし…
But...
ギアス　この力が
人を孤独にする というのなら
Geass... If this power dooms
its possessor to solitude,
俺はもっと耐える心を持たねばならない
then I need to strengthen
my heart even more.
そして マオに
And then I have to pay back
Mao for what he did!
この借りを！
CHEERING MAO